Guide to the American Library Association, Board of Education for Librarianship Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
American Library Association, Board of Education for Librarianship Records
1945-1954.
American Library Association. Board of Education for Librarianship.
3.5 linear ft (ca. 4,200 items in 8 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library,
4078567
History
Scope and Content
Correspondence, reports, and related materials of the American Library Association Board of Education for Librarianship from 1945 to 1954. The collection consists of carbon copies of letters from the files of two Board members: Richard H. Logsdon and Francis R. St. John. The correspondence is chiefly between Anita N. Hostetter, Secretary of the Board, and other Board members. These records concern library school programs, curricula, course outlines, examinations, accreditation, and related matters.
Subjects
Logsdon, Richard H. (Richard Henry), 1912-; St. John, Francis R.; Hostetter, Anita N.; Library science--Societies, etc.; Library education.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1973 M73-11-27 Logsdon, Richard H. Gift, transfer from the School of Library Science
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Board of Education for Librarianship Records
  - Board of Education for Librarianship, 1945-1954
    - 1945-1947 (Box 1)
    - 1948 (Box 2)
    - 1949 (Box 3)
    - 1950 January-September (Box 4)
    - 1950 October-1951 June (Box 5)
    - 1951 July-1954 (Box 6)
  - Library School Programs
    - Atlanta-Georgia Peabody (Box 7)
    - Illinois-West Virginia (Box 8)